Derrick Tawah



info@derricktawah.com



linkedin.com/in/derricktawah



+49 (0)1577 701 7232



https://github.com/DerrickTawah

Summary

#20+ years in B2B sales, with roles in sales, marketing, customer service, and product management.

#Helped build the ReachLocal business in Germany within Sales and Sales Operations roles.

#Experienced sales professional with a proven track record of sales to C-Level executives.

#Certified Agile Scrum Master, Product Owner, and Frontend Web Developer.

#Conceptualized and built NjangiList.com.

#Graduated in M.A. International Economics from the Berlin School of Economics and Law.

Experience



📕 Sales Area Manager

Hielscher Ultrasonics GmbH

Jul 2020 - Present (6 months +)

Hielscher Ultrasonics specializes in the design and manufacturing of high power ultrasonic homogenizers for lab, bench-top, and production level. Ultrasonic power is an effective and energy-efficient means to apply high shear and intense stress to liquids, powder/liquid mixtures, and slurries.

In this role, I am responsible for sales in the North American market (the US and Canada). This involves managing customer inquiries, consulting with customers on their requirements, customizing the right ultrasonic devices to meet customer requirements, closing sales, ensuring smooth after-sales delivery of devices, handling post-sales inquiries, and up-scaling/up-selling existing customers.



Owner

NjangiList

Jan 2016 - Present (5 years +)

NjangiList.com showcases interesting, creative, and innovative startup businesses from Africa.

As founder and owner, I am responsible for defining and driving the product/platform vision, determining and steering the product strategy, defining the product roadmap, conceptualizing and extending platform features through defining user stories and prioritizing these, and overall ensuring value is created for all users.

STRÖER Sales Operations Manager

Ströer SE & Co. KGaA

Jul 2018 - Mar 2019 (9 months)

Ströer is a leading German out-of-home advertising, online advertising, billboards, and street furniture company with headquarters in Cologne.

I joined Ströer through their acquisition of ReachLocal's assets in Germany. In my role at Ströer, I was primarily charged with ensuring a smooth migration of the customer base from ReachLocal to Ströer, including setting up the appropriate CRM dashboards, reports, and tools to monitor the migrations

process within the Salesforce CRM. Lastly, I worked closely with Regional Sales Managers to improve sales team productivity through optimising qualified lead generation.

Sales Operations Manager

ReachLocal

Jul 2011 - Jun 2018 (7 years)

ReachLocal offers comprehensive digital marketing services to help businesses reach their customers.

In this role, I was in charge of a team of 6 regional sales support managers, working closely with sales managers with dotted lines to the country manager. My team worked to support the sales teams increase sales and revenue: by removing impediments to sales, thus supporting sales teams to meet their sales targets and goals, defining and optimizing sales processes, providing product and process training to the sales teams in cooperation with the sales trainer. We were also responsible for managing, customizing, and displaying relevant information and data on all platforms (including Salesforce) to the sales teams. We also ensured that senior management and all stakeholders were provided with relevant reports on sales KPIs. Our team acted as a key link between the sales teams and other departments.

Digital Marketing Consulting

ReachLocal

Jan 2011 - Jun 2011 (6 months)

I joined ReachLocal as one of the first employees in the German operations. I helped lay the foundation for a successful start in the German market.

In this role, I did lead research and qualification through cold-calling, scheduled sales meetings online and offline, negotiated contract terms and closed deals, on-boarded new clients and consulted with these clients with the goal of defining clients' digital marketing strategy, created online campaign strategies, planned and ran digital marketing campaigns for clients, managed and monitored campaign performance against client expectations, and reported on campaign performance to clients and stakeholders

cultuzz. Sales and Product Manager

Cultuzz Digital Media GmbH

Oct 2009 - Sep 2010 (1 year)

Cultuzz Digital Media GmbH is an IT and Internet company that specializes in software for e-commerce in the travel and tourism industry.

In this role, I managed the sales process and acquired new clients in the travel and hospitality industry. I supported the Product Managers in defining specifications for new features for the Cultuzz hotel booking engine (CultBooking) and hotel property management software (CultDesk - #redundant) and created the corresponding acceptance criteria for these features. I tested the product increments against acceptance criteria as defined by the product managers.

Senior Sales Executive

marcus evans Group

Nov 2007 - May 2009 (1 year 7 months)

In this role, I managed sales of B2B events to C-level decision makers of national and multinational corporations

Education



BUSINESS TRENDS ACADEMY (BTA) GmbH

Software & Web Development, Software Development, Agile Scrum Project Management

2019 - 2020

#Python: threading, RESTful API, Numpy, Pandas, data mining, crawling and webscraper, Keras, Anaconda, Tensorflow, Neuronal Networks, functions, DB, GUI.

#Laravel: MVC, routing, migration, eloquent, OOP.

#Vue.js: components, forms, routing.

#Ruby on Rails: syntax, libraries, classes & objects, exceptions, MVC, action controller, view, web services.

#PHP, Javascript and SQL: webserver, OOP, Variables, Arrays and Operations, Sessions, MVC, Javascript & DOM, DOM Manipulation, AJAX, MYSQL introduction, DB Connection, CMS with login management.

Codecademy

Web Development, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript

2018 - 2018

Building Websites from Scratch with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript and JQuery

CF CareerFoundry

User Experience Designer, UX Design

2015 - 2016

Valuable knowledge on designing products for humans

The Interaction Design Foundation

User Centered Design, User Centered Design

2015 - 2015

Educational institution: www.interactiondesign.org

1 The Berlin School of Economics and Law

M.A., International Economics

2006 - 2007

International Economics with an Emphasis on Development Economics. Thesis on Renewal Energy

University of Benin

B.Sc. Hons, Economics

1993 - 1997

Benin-City, Edo State, Nigeria

Cameroon College of Arts, Science and Technology (CCAST) A Levels

1989 - 1991

Presbyterian Secondary School (P.S.S)

O/Levels 1984 - 1989

Licenses & Certifications

- Build Websites from Scratch Codecademy 11953885
- **⇒**XIN Agile Scrum Master EXIN
- CF User Experience Designer CareerFoundry
- FB Facebook Blueprint Facebook 170272-39031081
- Google Adwords Qualified Google 00972548
- **≅**XIN Agile Product Owner EXIN
- Bing Ads Microsoft
- Master of Arts International Economics The Berlin School of Economics and Law
- Bachelor of Science (B. Sc.) Economics University of Benin
- General Certificate of Education Advanced Level GCE Board
- General Certificate of Education Ordinary Level GCE Boar

Skills

Agile Methodologies • CSS • HTML5 • Digital Media • Social Media Marketing • Sales • Strategy • User Experience Design • Sales Management • Product Management

Honors & Awards

■ Employee of the Year - ReachLocal GmbH